Franz Alexander MD Papers Finding Aid
Oskar Diethelm Library
- Anita Alexander Files
  - Finances and receipts, most after Franz Alexander’s death, 1932; 1959; 1964 - 1965 (Box 10)
  - Condolences and memorials after Franz Alexander’s death, 1964; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Memberships, 1942; 1962; 1964 (Box 10)
  - Letters and cards to Anita, 1958 - 1964 (Box 10)
  - Programs and announcements including a program for an exhibit of Anita’s paintings and newspaper clippings about Anita’s paintings, 1935; 1943; 1949 (Box 10)
  - Pauline Phillips correspondence, who was the advice columnist, Dear Abby, and wrote under the pen name Abigail Van Buren. Letters to Anita signed Popo or Popita and includes a few original letters written to Dear Abby seeking advice, plus replies written as Dear Abby in addition to newspaper clippings of Dear Abby columns, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Art Institute, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Barta Camp for Girls correspondence, 1933 - 1934 (Box 10)
  - Findlay Galleries on sale of Anita Alexander’s painting, 1934 - 1935; 1938 (Box 10)
  - La Revue Moderne (Paris) review of Anita Alexander’s work, 1937 (Box 10)
  - “Neoterics,” a society to bring together painters and sculptors, 1935 - 1937 (Box 10)
  - Publicity, 1933 (Box 10)
  - Sterner Galleries correspondence, 1934 (Box 10)
- Reprints and Publications
  - List of reprint titles from original folders received from donor, Undated (Box 11)
  - Titles A-B, 1930 - 1950 (Box 11)
  - Titles C-D, 1935 - 1956 (Box 11)
  - Titles E-F, 1934 - 1950 (Box 11)
  - Titles H-I, 1935 - 1946 (Box 11)
  - Titles J-M, 1930 - 1946 (Box 12)
  - Titles N-O, 1926 - 1958 (Box 12)
  - Titles Pa-Psychi, 1935 - 1953 (Box 12)
  - Titles Psychoanalysis-, 1932 - 1956 (Box 12)
  - Titles Psychoanalyst-Psychosomatic, 1937 - 1955 (Box 13)
  - Titles Q-R, 1933 - 1943 (Box 13)
  - Titles S, 1931 - 1954 (Box 13)
  - Titles T, 1937 - 1956 (Box 13)
  - Titles U-V, 1933 - 1958 (Box 14)
  - Titles W-Z, 1944 - 1961 (Box 14)
  - Titles A-O (Foreign), 1925 - 1935 (Box 14)
  - Titles P-Z (Foreign), 1930 - 1955 (Box 14)
  - Reprints/Articles miscellaneous, Undated (Box 14)
  - Book reviews, discussions, introductions, 1934 - 1953 (Box 15)
  - Symposia, book reviews, meetings, 1934 - 1945 (Box 15)
  - Symposia, book reviews, meetings, 1934 - 1958 (Box 15)
  - World Book Encyclopedia, Chicago magazine article, misc. reprints, Undated (Box 15)
- Photographs
  - Franz Alexander portraits, 1964; Undated (Box 16)
  - Franz and Anita Alexander at an event, 1962 (Box 16)
  - Franz and Anita with a group at Fairmont Hotel, San Francisco including Pauline Phillips (Dear Abby), also signed by her, Undated (Box 16)
  - Two photos of Anita Alexander on horseback, Undated (Box 16)
  - Family photographs assorted, undated, mostly snapshots (Box 16)
  - Family photographs assorted, undated, mostly snapshots (Box 16)
  - Family photographs, vacations, 1938; Undated (Box 16)
  - Family photographs, vacations, Undated (Box 16)
  - Family photographs in Palm Springs, California, Undated (Box 16)
  - Family photographs, South Dakota and Utah, 1951 (Box 16)
  - Portrait of Silvia Alexander, inscribed to her mother, Undated (Box 16)
  - Photograph of unidentified children standing in a line, Undated (Box 16)
  - Photograph of a poster featuring a lecture by Franz Alexander, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Photograph of Franz Alexander with Dr. Thomas French, c. 1937 (Box 16)
  - Caricature drawing of an unidentified man, Undated (Box 17)
  - Portrait of Anita Alexander, Undated (Box 17)
  - Portrait of Franz Alexander for the Institute for Psychoanalysis, Chicago, Undated (Box 17)
  - Photograph of Anita, Kiki, and Silvia Alexander, c. 1934 (Box 17)
  - Photograph of Franz Alexander, photograph of Alexander in WWI military uniform, and 1927 photograph of Bernard Alexander, Franz’s father, Undated (Box 17)
  - 2 portraits, one of Anita Alexander and possibly one of daughter, Undated (Box 17)